pajiba.com 2019-11-30

# Privacy Policy | Pajiba

**Last Updated:** February 4, 2019.

Pajiba.com is a website owned and operated by Scathing Websites, LLL (“ **Pajiba** ”, “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”). In this privacy policy, we want to let you know:

—What information is collected by us;  
—What information is collected by third-party services and advertisers;  
—How that collected information is used; and  
—How and to what extent our readers can opt-out of such data collection.

**What information do we collect?**

The only information we collect directly from any of our readers and users is the information that our web host and webserver automatically receives and records in data logs from your browser, such as your IP address and the page requested. This information is securely stored on our web host’s network and is necessary for the operation, maintenance, and security of our webserver and this website.

We do not use this collected information for any purpose other than serving our website pages to you. We do not use this information, or any information collected by our service providers or advertisers (as discussed below), for any purpose other than to better serve our readers. Pajiba does not rent, sell or otherwise share personal information about you with other people or companies other than the ones identified below unless we are responding to subpoenas, court orders, or legal processes, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

**What third-party service providers do we use and what information do they collect?**

Our commenting platform is operated and maintained by Disqus, Inc. (“ **Disqus** ”). When you submit a comment or otherwise interact with the comments through Disqus’ platform, Disqus may collect certain personal information of yours, including your name, e-mail address, and IP address. Please see [the Disqus Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy) for more information including how to opt-out of Disqus’ information collection. 

We also use certain analytics service providers to, among other things, understand what content our readers enjoy by tracking user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, maintaining records of past activity in order to provide better service when visitors return to our site, and using browser or device information to customize page content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. 

These are the analytics service providers we currently use, either actively or from time-to-time, along with links to their respective privacy policies for more information including (where they provide such information) how to individually opt out of their analytics tracking:

— **Google LLC** \- [Google Analytics’ Privacy Policy, a.k.a., “how Google uses data”](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
— **Chartbeat, Inc.** \- [Chartbeat’s Privacy Policy](https://chartbeat.com/privacy/)  
— **Statcounter** \- [Statcounter’s Privacy Policy](https://statcounter.com/about/legal/)

Our EU readers can opt of analytics tracking, as discussed below, though we hope you won’t as it only allows us to better understand our readers and serve your interests.

**What third-party advertisers do we use and what information do they collect?**

We use several third-party advertisers who serve either personalized or non-personalized ads. These advertisers typically use cookies or web beacons on our site which collect certain information and sends its back to these advertisers. Except for our EU readers who can opt out of personal information collection, as discussed below, we do not have access to or control over these cookies or the collection of information once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. For more on that, we turn to the NAI disclaimer:

> We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

As a result of your visit to our site and not opting out of advertising information collection, these advertising partners may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address, your ISP, your browser type, and your clickstream information. This information is used by them to serve personalized (e.g., based on a user’s location, prior site visits and/or visits to other sites on the internet) and/or non-personalized advertising. If you opt-out of this collection, you may still see advertisements where our advertiser partners are able to serve ads without the use of cookies or scripts to collect information, but they will be non-personalized and not based upon any of your information. These are the advertisers we currently use, either actively or from time-to-time, along with links to their respective privacy policies:

— **Publisher First, Inc. (Freestar)** \- [Freestar’s Platform Privacy Policy](https://freestar.io/data-policy/) and [Freestar’s Website Privacy Policy](https://freestar.io/privacy-policy/)  
— **7hops.com, Inc. (ZergNet)** \- [ZergNet’s Privacy Policy](https://www.zergnet.com/privacy)  
— **GumGum, Inc.** \- [Gumgum’s Privacy Policy](https://gumgum.com/privacy-policy), [GumGum’s Cookie Policy](https://gumgum.com/cookies-policy) and [GumGum’s Opt-Out and Ad Preferences Statement](https://gumgum.com/opt-out)  
— **Unruly Group Limited** \- [Unruly’s Privacy Policy](https://unruly.co/privacy/) and [Unruly’s GDPR Commitment Statement](https://unruly.co/gdpr/)  
— **Google AdSense** \- [Google Privacy Policies](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

**Do we ever update this policy?**

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Web site here on this page to notify you of these changes. Where the policies include changes to how we or our partners collect or use your personal information, or where new partners are permitted to collect certain information, that will also be reflected here and EU readers will be given an opportunity to opt-out of such collection and use.

If you are concerned about how your information is used, please periodically check back to this page.

**Can you opt out of our data collection?**

Our EU readers (readers visiting us from European Economic Area countries subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation) will see a consent notice upon their first visit to this site. Our partners will only collect your information, in accordance with the terms above, if you affirmatively indicate consent to such collection and our use of cookies. If you give consent and would later like to revoke it, please contact us and we can work that out for you. If you would like to exercise any other rights under the GDPR, please contact us with your request.

At this time, we don’t offer the ability for our non-EU readers to similarly opt out. However, you can visit the NAI’s [Opt Out of Interest-Based Advertising](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) for more information on opting out of targeted advertising, in addition to visiting the individual privacy policies included above. You can also visit [Google’s Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), the  Digital Advertising Alliance (the DAA), and the DAA’s [User’s Current IBA Status Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) to learn more and find other ways to limit what information advertisers collect.

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us via the contact information included below, you can contact the DMA’s Committee on Ethical Business Practices at mgoldberger@the-dma.org, or you can contact the Federal Trade Commission by phone at 202.FTC-HELP (202.382.4357) or electronically at http://www.ftc.gov/ftc/complaint.htm.

**How can you contact us?**

If you have any questions about anything in this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us. We can be reached via e-mail at [pajiba@gmail.com](mailto:pajiba@gmail.com). If you wish to reach out via old-fashioned mail, our addresses are:

**Editorial Offices** | **Business Offices**  
---|---  
Scathing Websites LLC  
102 Ashmont Street  
Portland, ME 04103 |  Scathing Websites LLC  
950 4th Street, #303  
Santa Monica, CA 90403
